Vincent Price Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1920-1992 (Box 200-230)
  - Hollywood Museum, Hollywood, Calif., 1960-1968
  - Honors, awards, and tributes
    - Awards, 1945, 1965, 1971, 1980-1992
    - Film retrospectives, 1980-1991
    - Honorary degrees, 1955, 1963
    - Honors and tributes, 1956-1962, 1982-1990, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1990, undated (Box 214)
  - Horror film events and societies, 1971-1972, 1987, undated
  - Hotels and lodgings, 1961-1970, undated
  - House & Garden, 1966-1970
  - House of the Six Directions, Scottsdale, Ariz., 1962-1971, 1978
  - Indian Art of America Committee, 1958, undated
  - Insurance
    - Appraisals, 1948, 1965-1969, 1985, (2 folders)
    - Claims, 1964-1969
  - Interior Department
    - Center for Arts of Indian America, 1966-1968
    - Indian Arts and Crafts Board (Box 215)
      - 1962-1964, (8 folders)
      - 1965-1966, (5 folders) (Box 216)
      - 1967-1968, (9 folders) (Box 217)
      - 1969, (7 folders) (Box 218)
      - 1970-1971, (9 folders) (Box 219)
      - 1974 (Box 220)
      - Undated, (3 folders)
    - Institute of American Indian Arts
      - General, 1963-1973, 1987, undated, (2 folders)
      - Vincent Price awards in creative writing, 1963-1972, (2 folders) (Box 221)
  - International Design Center, Los Angeles, Calif., 1963-1964
  - Interviews and questionnaires
    - David Del Valle, 1987
    - KALX radio, San Francisco, Calif., telephone interview, January 15, 1988
    - KCET Magazine, 1989
    - Miscellaneous
    - National Art Education Association, 1965
  - Joslyn Art Museum, Omaha, Neb., 1974-1975, 1988
  - Junior Arts Center at Barnsdall Park, Los Angeles, Calif., 1965-1970, undated
  - Junior Programs of California, 1962-1965, undated
  - La Jolla Playhouse, La Jolla, Calif., 1971, 1987
  - Leonard Wood Memorial for the Eradication of Leprosy, 1968
  - Library of Congress, Washington, D.C., 1963-1972, 1988-1990
  - Lincoln-Douglas debates, undated
  - The Little Gallery, Beverly Hills, Calif., 1943-1944
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, Calif., 1958-1975, 1984-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 222)
  - Magazines, 1968-1970, undated
  - Mayor's Celebrities Committee, 1967-1968
  - Medical records, 1985-1990
  - Memberships, 1962-1971
  - Miscellaneous textual materials, 1960-1985, undated, (4 folders) (Box 223)
  - Miss America Pageant, 1966-1968, (4 folders)
  - Modern Institute of Art, Beverly Hills, Calif. (Box 224)
    - 1948-1949, undated See also Oversize
  - Museum of African Art, Washington, D.C., 1965-1966
  - Museum of the American Indian, New York, N.Y., 1959-1990, undated
  - New York Graphic Society, 1958-1960, undated
  - Northeast Missouri State University, Kirksville, Mo., 1980-1992, undated, (2 folders)
  - Northwood Institute, Midland, Mich., 1966-1971. undated
  - Notes
    - By others, 1935, 1948-1986, undated
    - By Price, 1963-1990, undated, (2 folders)
  - Ohio Wesleyan University, Delaware, Ohio, 1957-1966, undated (Box 225)
  - O'Neil, Barbara, 1937-1938, 1980-1986, undated
  - Parish, James Robert and Stephen Whitney, Vincent Price Unmasked: A Biography, 1973-1974, (2 folders)
  - Performing Arts Council of the Music Center, Los Angeles, Calif., 1961-1966 See also Oversize
  - Pets, 1960-1970, 1984-1990, undated
  - Projects
    - Cooking show, 1968-1969, undated
    - "Food with a View," 1969, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1970-1974, undated
    - Restaurant, 1967-1968, undated
    - Vincent Price Theatre, proposed, 1964-1965, undated
  - Rand, McNally & Co., 1966-1968
  - Recipes, 1964-1967, undated, (3 folders) (Box 226)
  - Residences and other real estate, 1942, 1951-1990, undated, (3 folders)
  - Riverdale Country Day School, Riverdale, N.Y., 1934
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1964-1970 (Box 227)
  - St. Louis Art Museum, St. Louis, Mo., 1964-1975, 1981-1990
  - St. Louis Country Day School, St. Louis, Mo., circa1923-1929, 1954-1988, undated, (2 folders)
  - Scripps College, Claremont, Calif., 1950, 1959-1966, (3 folders)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, New York, N.Y., 1960-1965
  - Society for the Friends of Count Agoston Haraszthy, 1966-1967 (Box 228)
  - Staff
    - Household duties and schedules, 1964-1967
    - Miscellany, 1964-1969, undated
    - Notes and reports from office staff, 1963-1970, 1989, undated, (2 folders)
  - Telephone messages, 1962-1984, undated
  - Theatre and Arts Foundation of San Diego County, Calif., 1963-1967
  - Toledo Museum of Art, Toledo, Ohio, 1984-1988, undated
  - Travel
    - Miscellany, 1928, 1964-1975
    - Passports and other documents, 1932, 1949, 1965, undated
  - University Film Study Center, Cambridge, Mass., 1970-1974 (Box 229)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Calif.
    - Art Council, 1953-1988, undated, (4 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1962, 1969-1978, undated
  - University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Calif., 1964-1969, 1979, undated
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Richmond, Va., 1962-1970, undated (Box 230)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, N.Y., 1957-1966, undated
  - The Wilderness Society, 1968-1970
  - The Wisdom Society, 1965-1988
  - Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
    - Alumni materials, 1963-1992, undated, (2 folders)
    - Art Gallery, 1977, 1988-1992
    - Film Study Center, 1983-1987, undated
    - Miscellany, 1969, 1976-1989
    - Student materials, 1932-1934, undated
  - Young actors on tour, 1967
- Oversize, 1938-1991 (Box OV 1-OV 8)
  Oversize material consisting of large illustrated letters, posters, programs, scrapbooks, and a computer printout.
  Described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - General Correspondence (Box OV 1)
    - Sept. 1963 (Container 8)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Company Files (Box OV 2)
    - Vincent Price Collection of Fine Art
      - Charts, reports, and analysis
        - Inventory, 1966 (Container 95)
  - Stage, Screen, and Studio Files (Box OV 3)
    - Films
      - Theatre of Blood, circa 1972 (Container 142)
    - Lectures
      - Feb. 1971 (Container 147)
    - Miscellaneous files (Box OV 4)
      - Public appearances
        - Various events, 1938 (Container 152)
    - Plays (Box OV 5)
      - Diversions and Delights
        - Promotional material and advertisements, 1978-1980 (Container 177)
        - Oliver! 1976 (Container 179)
  - Subject File
    - Drawings and sketches
      - By others, 1971-1991, undated (Container 209)
    - East Los Angeles College, Monterey Park, Calif.
      - Vincent Price Gallery, undated (Container 210)
    - Fan materials (Box OV 6)
      - Miscellany, 1975 (Container 211)
    - Modern Institute of Art, Beverly Hills, Calif., undated (Container 224) (Box OV 7)
    - Performing Arts Council of the Music Center, Los Angeles, Calif., 1961 (Container 225) (Box OV 8)